Zachary DeNoto

Data Analyst

585-683-8068 • Rochester, NY https://zacharydenoto.github.io/ z.denoto@gmail.com

RESUME OBJECTIVE

Data Analyst with 6 + years of experience executing data-driven solutions to increase efficiency, accuracy and internal data processing. Experienced at creating and using data models for predictive analytics to deliver insights to complex business problems.

SKILLS

• Python

• R

• Pandas, Scikit-learn

Tableau

Spark

Keras

Tensorflow

SOL

Alteryx

VBA

EXPERIENCE

Patra Corp Remote

Data Analyst August 2021-present

- Manage and build new data visualizations, ensuring the most accurate real life figures for executives.
- Responsible for the use of SQL Server Management Studio (SSMS), creating custom SQL queries retrieving data from multiple data sources.
- Perform ad-hoc analytics to engineer new solutions tackling complex problems using various technologies.
- Construct custom Python scripts or VBA Macros speeding up manual tasks currently being done in days to seconds

Peko Precision Products Rochester, NY

Data Analyst

August 2018-July 2021

- Create weekly and monthly advanced Tableau or Python visualizations using libraries such as Matplotlib, ggplot, and Plotly from data outputs based on the reports needed.
- Write Python scripts to replace manual Excel data manipulation or VBA Macros resulting in report run time from hours to seconds.
- Pulled, manipulated, and joined data from SQL servers using Alteryx and ERP software to integrate multiple data sources.
- Designed and implemented Python scripts utilizing Pandas library to alter ERP report outputs or SQL data sources to create more efficient, fast data solutions.

Arthur J Gallagher Rochester, NY

Analyst

June 2016-August 2018

- Collected, processed, and visualized data for over 20 companies moving C-level executives globally.
- Designed and programmed VBA Macros to reconcile errors in international employees' compensation documentation.
- Created custom formulas and spreadsheets in Excel to automatically input data, increasing productivity resulting in decreased time spent on data retrieval and input.

EDUCATION

Bellevue University

Bellevue, NE

Master of Science (MS) in Data Science

June 2021

Saint Joseph's University

Philadelphia, PA

Bachelor of Science (BS) in Leadership, Ethics and Organizational Sustainability (LEO)

May 2015